A Guide for the Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society, Office Files of Lisa Jordan FA589
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society, Office Files of Lisa Jordan
2000-2008
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA589
1.7 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Arrangement
Alphabetical
Ford Foundation
- African Forum and Network on Debt and Development, 2004 (Box 1)
- Bank Information Center (BIC) -- Transparency Campaign, 2002 (Box 1)
- Bank Information Center (BIC)'s Afghanistan Project, 2002 (Box 1)
- Bank Information Center (BIC), 2003-2004 (Box 1)
- Bank Information Center (BIC), 2004 (Box 1)
- Bank Information Center (BIC) -- Strategic Planning Workshop, Oct 3-5, 2008 (Box 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  File is closed to scholarly research.
  Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Open to scholarly research in 2019.
- Bank Information Center (BIC) -- Documents, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
- Bridge Initiative, 2004 (Box 1)
- Bridge Initiative, 2005-2006 (Box 1)
  Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Open to scholarly research in 2017.
- CIVICUS, 2003-2006 (Box 1)
- CIVICUS, 2006-2008 (Box 1)
- DOCIP, 2006-2007 (Box 1)
  Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Open to scholarly research in 2018.
- Earth Rights, 2003-2007 (Box 1)
  Some of the records in this file are restricted because they are less than 10 years old. The restricted items have been segregated and are inaccessible. The file is open to research, and physical removal of the segregated material is not necessary. Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2017.
- Government Accountability Project (GAP), 2004-2008 (Box 1)
  Some of the records in this file are restricted because they are less than 10 years old. The restricted items have been segregated and are inaccessible. The file is open to research, and physical removal of the segregated material is not necessary. Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2019.
- Grassroots Organizations Operating Together in Sisterhook (GROOTS), 2005 (Box 1)
- Humanitarian Accountability Project, 2002-2007 (Box 1)
  Some of the records in this file are restricted because they are less than 10 years old. The restricted items have been segregated and are inaccessible. The file is open to research, and physical removal of the segregated material is not necessary. Date Restricted Material -- Contains records less than 10 years old -- Restricted records are Open to scholarly research in 2018.
- Institute for Agriculture and Trade Policy (IATP) (1/3), 2002-2008 (Box 1)
- Institute for Agriculture and Trade Policy (IATP) (2/3), 2002-2008 (Box 1)
- Institute for Agriculture and Trade Policy (IATP) (3/3), 2002-2008 (Box 1)
- Institute for Research and Debate on Governance (IRG), Sep 2008 (Box 1)
  Date restricted material - Open to scholarly research in 2019.
- InterAction, 2004-2006 (Box 1)
- International NGO Forum on Indonesian Development (INFID), 2003-2004 (Box 1)
- International Rivers Network (IRN), 2001-2005 (Box 2)
- London School of Economics, 2004 (Box 2)
- Open Democracy, 2002-2004 (Box 2)
- Shackdwellers, 2005 (Box 2)
- Syracuse University (Milton Mueller), 2004-2005 (Box 2)
- Transparency International (TI), 2000 (Box 2)